Finding aid to William Dodge Gray papers CA.MS.01127
Smith College Archives
William Dodge Gray papers
1913-1958
Smith College Archives
Gray, William Dodge, 1878-1958
CA.MS.01127
1.75 linear feet (3 containers)
William Dodge Gray was a scholar and professor of History and Latin at Smith College. These papers contain correspondence, photographs, publications, notes and news clippings documenting his education and career.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Source unknown
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Biographical / Historical
William Dodge Gray was born in Little Rock, Arkansas, on May 6, 1878 to Lucy Dodge and Daniel Lewis Gray. He graduated from the University of Arkansas in 1900 with an A.B and went on to be principal of Springdale High School in Arkansas, before entering Cornell in 1902. Gray received his M.A from Cornell in 1903 and his Ph.D. from Cornell in 1907. In 1907, Gray became Instructor of History and Latin, where he could pursue his interest in Classical history and Archeology. He wrote many articles on Classical History and Archaeology. He was a member of Phi Beta Kappa, the American Historical Association, the American Philological Association, the Archaeological Institute of America and Chairman of the History Department. Gray retired in 1946. He died in 1958, at the age of 80, after a long illness. He was survived by his wife, Henrietta Seelye '98, and their three daughters, Henrietta Gray McBee '35, Marian Gray Warren '38 and Lucy Gray Martin '38.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains correspondence, photographs, publications, notebooks, and lecture notes from William Dodge Gray's time working at Smith, from 1907-1946. The collection also contains several news clippings and obituaries documenting Gray's later years after retiring from Smith.
Gray, William Dodge, 1878-1958
- Biographical information including Smith faculty forms and newspaper clippings, 1916-1958 (Box 831.1, Folder 1)
- Lecture Notes – History 32, 1920-1923 (Box 831.1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence – Houses in Little Rock, 1936 (Box 831.1, Folder 4)
- Notes – Miscellaneous, undated (Box 831.1, Folder 5)
- Various publications by Professor Gray, 1916-1943 (Box 831.1, Folder 6)
- Seven notebooks including from Columbia, Pantheon Etruscan notes, Ruggieno Secular Book V, Tut-Ankh-Amen for Miss Seevers, 1913-1930 (Box 831.1)
- First Great Journey of Hadrian - draft, undated (Box 832, Folder 1)
- History of Civilization – draft – Ch.I Paleolithic, undated (Box 832, Folder 2)
- History of Civilization – draft – Ch.II Neolithic, undated (Box 832, Folder 3)
- History of Civilization – draft – Ch.III Ancient Near orient to 500 B.C., undated (Box 832, Folder 4)
- Impressions of Hadrian's Wall – draft, undated (Box 832, Folder 5)
- Life of Hadrian – draft Ch. II and III, undated (Box 832, Folder 6)
- Life of Hadrian – draft Ch. IV and V, undated (Box 832, Folder 7)
- Notes on Hadrian, undated (Box 832, Folder 8)
- The Roman World in Great Britain, undated (Box 832, Folder 9)
- Some Gleanings in Etruscan Fields, undated (Box 832, Folder 10)
- Oversize sketches,The Roman Wall in Great Britain, undated (Box 832.1)